Register of the American Relief Administration Russian operational records
Hoover Institution Archives
- New York Office, Subject File, 1919-1924
  - Moscow headquarters
    - Liaison Division
      - History (Box 52)
        - Lehrs, J. H., 1921 December 22-1923 July (Folder 2)
      - Memoranda (1-6) (Folder 3)
      - Repatriation
        - Ekaterinoslav (Folder 4)
        - Elizavetgrad (Folder 5)
        - Gomel (Folder 6)
        - Kiev (Folder 7)
        - Kiev (Box 53, Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 70
        - Minsk (Folder 2)
        - Odessa (Folder 3)
          Available on microfilm reel 70 or 71
        - Petrograd (Box 54, Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 71
        - Rostov-Tsaritsyn (Folder 2)
        - Saratov (Folder 3)
        - Simbirsk (Folder 4)
        - Ufa (Folder 5)
        - Vitebsk (Folder 6)
      - Repatriation lists (Box 55)
        - A-B (Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 72
        - C-D (Folder 2)
          Available on microfilm reel 72A
        - E-F (Folder 3)
        - G (Box 56, Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 73
        - H-J (Folder 2)
        - K (Folder 3)
          Available on microfilm reel 74
        - L-O (Box 57, Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 75
        - P-R (Folder 2)
        - S (Box 58, Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 76
        - T-Z (Folder 2)
          Available on microfilm reel 77
      - Reports (Box 59)
        - For period from beginning of operations to, 1922 July 1 (Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 78
        - Miscellaneous (Folder 2)
        - Weekly (Folder 3)
    - Medical Division
      - General (Folder 4)
      - Accounting (Folder 5)
      - Charts (Folder 6)
      - Circular letters, (1-35) (Box 60, Folder 1)
        Available on microfilm reel 79
      - Disease prevention, delousing, etc. (Folder 2)
      - Disease prevention and inoculation campaign (Folder 3)
      - History (Henry Beeuwkes), 1921 September-1923 June (Folder 4)
      - Memoranda (1-9) (Folder 5)
      - Reports
        - Final reports from districts (Pelidici System, Kazau). Saratov final report is in Appendix IV of Saratov History (Folder 6)
        - Miscellaneous, n.d. and 1921-1923 (Folder 7)
          Available on microfilm reel 80
        - Monthly reports of medical director, 1921 September-1922 December (Box 61, Folder 1)
        - Supplementary report, 1923 June (Folder 2)
      - Sanitary trains, 1 and 2 (Folder 3)
      - Supplies
        - General (Folder 4)
        - Riga (Folder 5)
          Available on microfilm reel 81
      - Water purification program (Folder 6)
    - Memoranda
      - General (1-88) (Folder 7)
      - District (1-61) (Folder 8)
      - Headquarters (Box 62, Folder 1)
      - Office (1-159, 92-98 missing) (Folder 2)
      - Special (1-505, 486 missing) (Folder 3)
        Available on microfilm reel 82
    - Motor transportation (Folder 4)
    - Supply Division
      - General (Folder 5)
      - Correspondence (Box 63)
        - Commissar of Ways and Communications (Delgas)
          - Incoming nos. 26/339-43-43/012028, 1922 May 4-1923 June 2 (Folder 1)
            Available on microfilm reel 83
          - Outgoing nos. 938-4124, 1922 February 14-1923 June 14 (Folder 2)
        - Soviet government (Folder 3)
          Available on microfilm reel 83 or 84
      - History (W. C. McMahon) (Box 64, Folder 1)
        Available on microfilm reel 84
      - Memoranda (1-25) (Folder 2)
      - Report of Boinia Yard, 1921 September-1923 May (Folder 3)
    - Traffic Division
      - General (Folder 4)
      - Memoranda (1-2) (Folder 5)
  - Moving pictures (Folder 6)
  - Near East Relief (and Smyrna) (Folder 7)
  - New Economic Policy (Folder 8)
  - New York News Letter, 1921 December 24-1922 September 2 (Folder 9)
  - New York News Letter, 1921 December 24-1922 September 2 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    Available on microfilm reel 85
  - Nizhnii Novgorod (Folder 2)
  - North Russian Provident Association (Folder 3)
  - Oats (Folder 4)
  - Orenburg
    - General
      - 1922-1923 (Folder 5-7)
      - 1923 (Folder 8)
        Available on microfilm reel 86
      - 1923 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Adult feeding - Corn (Folder 2)
    - Agreement of A.R.A. concluded with institutions and private persons (Folder 3)
    - Certificates and mandates of A.R.A. (Folder 4)
    - Child feeding (Folder 5)
    - Correspondence
      - A.R.A. Warehouse (Folder 6)
      - Government
        - General
          - General (Folder 7)
            Available on microfilm reel 87
          - Undated and, 1922 January-May (Folder 8)
          - 1922 June-July (Box 67, Folder 1)
            Available on microfilm reel 88
          - 1922 August (Folder 2)
            Available on microfilm reel 88A
          - 1922 September-October (Box 68, Folder 1)
            Available on microfilm reel 89
        - Representative about railroad tickets for A.R.A. employees (Folder 2)
      - Inspection Division (Folder 3)
      - Traffic Division (Folder 4)
    - Finance (Folder 5)
    - History. General (relief in the Orsk region of the Orenburg); Buckley, Harold R., 19; Coleman, W. H. A., Hartridge, L. Engle, Lyon, F. B., 1922 August 1922 September 1; 1923 January-July; 1923 April 18 (Folder 6)
    - Kirghiz Republic (Folder 7)
    - Medical supplies (Folder 8)
    - Newspaper articles (Folder 9)
    - Printing orders through the government representative for A.R.A. offices (Folder 10)
    - Refugees - Soup kitchens (Folder 11)
    - Reports
      - General (Folder 12)
      - Medical (Folder 13)
        Available on microfilm reel 90
    - Seed allocation (Folder 14)
    - Transportation (Folder 15)
    - Warehouses (Folder 16)
  - Passports (Folder 17)
  - Pelidisi table (Folder 18)
  - Pellagra report (Folder 19)
  - Personnel (Box 69)
    - General
      - Undated and 1921 (Folder 1)
      - 1922-1923 (Folder 2)
    - A-B (Folder 3)
      Available on microfilm reel 91
    - C-F (Folder 4)
    - G-H (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - I-L (Folder 2)
    - M-P (Folder 3)
    - Q-R (Folder 4)
      Available on microfilm reel 92
    - S-Z (Folder 5)
    - Blandy, Harold (Folder 6)
    - Field work (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Jews (Folder 2)
    - Records with photographs (Folder 3)
    - Rejections (Folder 4)
      Available on microfilm reel 93
    - Rosters, 1921 September 24-1923 July (Folder 5)
    - Russian Historical Division (Folder 6)
    - Russian labor (Folder 7)
    - Russians (Box 72)
      - General
        - 1921 December 21-1923 May (Folder 1)
        - A-Z (Folder 2)
      - Certificate of appreciation (Folder 3)
      - Forms (Folder 4)
        Available on microfilm reel 94
    - Shield, Philip B. (Folder 5)
    - Subsistance (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 2)
  - Petrograd
    - General (Folder 3)
      Available on microfilm reel 95
    - Child feeding (Folder 4)
    - Children's homes (Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with Soviet government
      - Incoming
        - (53-3895), 1921 November 26-1922 October 16 (Folder 6)
        - (118-1881), 1922 October 25-1923 June 16 (Box 74, Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 96
      - Outgoing
        - (1-434), 1921 November 14-1922 March (Folder 2)
          Available on microfilm reel 96A
        - (435-700), 1922 March 6-1922 August 16 (Folder 3)
        - (701-1028), 1922 August 17-1923 June 18 (Box 75, Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 97
    - Correspondence with Soviet government representation (Folder 2)
    - Finance (Folder 3)
    - Food remittances
      - General (Folder 4)
        Available on microfilm reel 97 or 98
      - Keeny, S. M. Reports (Folder 5)
    - History
      - Keeny, S. M. (Folder 6)
      - Renshaw, Donald. Includes unfinished history by Herschel C. Walker (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Intelligentsia (Folder 2)
      Available on microfilm reel 98
    - Personnel (Folder 3)
    - Refugees (Folder 4)
    - Reports
      - General (Folder 5)
      - Medical (Folder 6)
    - Student feeding, n.d. and 1922-1924 (Folder 7)
    - Transportation (Folder 8)
    - Warehouses (Folder 9)
  - Political conditions (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Population
    - General (Folder 2)
    - By district - District boundaries (Folder 3)
      Available on microfilm reel 99
  - Ports
    - General
      - General (Folder 4)
      - Reports (Box 78, Folder 1)
        Available on microfilm reel 99A
      - Total arrivals (Folder 2)
    - Baltic history (duplicates of separate reports on Libau, Reval, Riga, Windau) (Folder 3)
    - Baltic operations. Review, 1921 August-1923 May (Folder 4)
    - Batum (Folder 5)
      Available on microfilm reel 100
    - Danzig (Folder 6)
    - Feodosia
      - General (Folder 7)
      - History (Folder 8)
    - Hango (Folder 9)
    - Libau (Folder 10)
    - Murmansk (Folder 11)
    - Nikolaev (Folder 12)
    - Novorossisk (Folder 13)
    - Odessa
      - General (Folder 14)
      - Correspondence with government (Folder 15)
      - Exports and imports, 1913 (Folder 16)
      - Letters from London, (1-88), 1922 February 10 -October 16 (Box 79, Folder 1)
        Available on microfilm reel 101
      - Telegrams to and from London (to,; from, 1922 March 27 -August 18 1922 February 24 -July 19) (Folder 2)
    - Petrograd
      - General (Folder 3)
      - Finance (Folder 4)
      - Reports (Folder 5)
    - Reval
      - General (Folder 6)
      - Supply Division (Folder 7)
    - Riga
      - General (Folder 8)
      - Supply Division (Folder 9)
    - Windau (Box 80)
      - General (Folder 1)
        Available on microfilm reel 102
      - Supply Division (Folder 2)
  - Press articles
    - "Story of the A.R.A. Russian Relief Program," Modern Miller (Folder 3)
    - "The A.R.A. Russian Operations at a Glance" (Folder 4)
    - Brooks, Sidney, "A.R.A. in Russia" and "American Aid to Europe through Mr. Hoover" (Folder 5)
    - Brown, E. H., "Some Unofficial Relations with Soviet Russia" (Folder 6)
    - Dickinson, T. H., "Russia in the Red Shadow" (Folder 7)
    - Egan, E. F., "Exposed to Bolshevism," Saturday Evening Post (Folder 8)
    - Fisher, H. H.
      - "Russian Peasants Robbed by New Economic Policy" (Folder 9)
      - "Russian Sketches," Survey. Includes clippings (Folder 10)
    - Foucar, F. H., resume of expenses and work accomplished in Russia with the A.R.A., 1921-1923 (Folder 11)
    - Gibson, Harold, "Laughter in Russia" (Folder 12)
    - Goldman, E., articles in World (Folder 13)
    - Goldstein, Sand and Klohs, W., "Kuzbas Story" (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Kelly, W. J., articles in New York Evening Post (Folder 2)
    - McCullagh, F., "Russian State under Bolshevism," New York Herald (Folder 3)
    - Mackenzie, F. A., articles in Globe (New York) (Folder 4)
      Available on microfilm reel 103
    - Noel, P., articles on Russia (Folder 5)
    - Ramsey, W. H., summary of the A.R.A. work in Russia from and "A Year of the A.R.A. in Russia", August 1921 to August 1922 (Folder 6)
    - Ruhl, A., "What I've Just Seen in Russia," Outlook, New York Tribune, Herald, etc. (Folder 7)
    - Shafroth, William C., "The Fact Story of the Russian Famine" (Folder 8)
    - Sheridan, C., "Russia in 1920-23," New York World (Folder 9)
    - Speavach, S., "Behind the Red Curtain," New York World and Russian articles in New York World (Folder 10)
    - Zimand, S., "Russia under the New Economic Policy," New York Tribune (Folder 11)
  - Press comment (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - Press summaries
    - Communications Division, "Daily News Summary,", 1921 October 7-1923 July 14 (Folder 2)
      Available on microfilm reel 103A
    - Fisher, H. H.
      - "Press and Economic Summaries"
        - 1920 September-1922 September (Folder 3)
          Available on microfilm reel 104
        - 1921 April-1922 September (Folder 4)
      - "Russian Notes," (1-62), 1922 October 26-1923 June 27 (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - "Russian Press Summary,", 1920 December 17-1922 October 21 (Folder 2)
    - Historical Division, "Review of the Moscow Press,", 1922 October 15-1923 June 30 (Folder 3)
    - Rossbluffdope, (1-36), 1923 January 27 -April 21 (Folder 4)
      Available on microfilm reel 104 or 105
  - Prisoners of war (Box 84, Folder 1)
    Available on microfilm reel 105
  - Programs
    - General (Folder 2)
    - Allocations
      - General (Folder 3)
      - Recommended (Folder 4)
    - Estimates (Folder 5)
    - Protection (Folder 6)
    - Rations (Box 85, Folder 1)
      Available on microfilm reel 106
  - Purchases
    - General (Folder 2)
    - Reports, 1921 October-1923 May
      - General (Folder 3)
      - Flour and corn grits (Folder 4)
  - Purchasing Commission
    - General (Folder 5)
    - Cards (Folder 6)
      Available on microfilm reel 107
    - Press releases (Folder 7)
  - R.A.K.P.D. (Box 86)
    - General (Folder 1)
    - Memoranda (1-4) (Folder 2)
  - Refugees
    - General (Folder 4)
    - Children (Folder 5)
      Available on microfilm reel 108
    - Constantinople
      - General
        - 1921 November-1922 December (Folder 6)
        - 1923 January-November; 1924 January-February (Box 87, Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 109
      - Agreement - League of Nations and the A.R.A. (Folder 2)
    - Crimea (Folder 3)
    - Philippine Island (Folder 4)
    - Reports (Folder 5)
    - Soup kitchens (Folder 6)
  - Relief organizations
    - General
      - 1921 July 27-1922 July 29 (Folder 7)
      - 1922 August 1-1923 August 24, 1924 February 14 (Folder 8)
        Available on microfilm reel 110
    - American Red Cross (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - Australia (Folder 2)
    - Belgium (Folder 3)
    - Canada (Folder 4)
    - Czechoslovakia (Folder 5)
    - Denmark (Folder 6)
    - Estonia (Folder 7)
    - Finland (Folder 8)
    - France (Folder 9)
    - Germany (Folder 10)
    - Great Britain (Folder 11)
    - Harbin Relief Committee (Folder 12)
    - International (Folder 13)
    - International Labor Commission (Folder 14)
    - Italy (Folder 15)
    - Jewish United Committee for the Relief of Pogrom Sufferers (Folder 16)
    - Joint Distribution Committee (Box 89)
      - General
        - 1921-1922 (Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 111
        - 1923-1924 (Folder 2)
      - Letters
        - General, (1-270), 1922 November 6-1923 July 2 (Folder 3)
          Available on microfilm reel 112
        - Accounting, 1923 February 17-June 28 (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - Lady Muriel Pagets' Mission (Folder 2)
    - Lander report on foreign relief organizations (Folder 3)
    - Nansen, Fritjof (Folder 4)
    - Navy co-operation (Folder 5)
    - Netherlands (Folder 6)
      Available on microfilm reel 113
    - Norway (Folder 7)
    - Poland (Folder 8)
    - Quakers (American Friends Service Committee) (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - Radical
      - General (Folder 2-4)
        Available on microfilm reels 113 and 114
      - American Committee for Russian Famine Relief (Liggett - Richey) (Folder 5)
        Available on microfilm reel 114
      - American Federated Russian Famine Relief Committee (Folder 6)
      - Friends of Soviet Russia (Folder 7)
      - Hibben, Paxton (Box 92, Folder 1)
      - Marsh - Norris (Folder 2)
      - Russian Famine Cooperating Organization (Folder 3)
        Available on microfilm reel 115
      - Russian Red Cross (D. H. Dubrowsky) (Folder 4-5)
    - Save the Children Fund (Folder 6)
    - Seventh Day Adventist (Folder 7)
    - Sweden (Folder 8)
    - Switzerland (Folder 9)
    - Ukrainian Federation of Jews (Folder 10)
    - Volga Relief Society, 1921-1924 (Folder 11)
    - Young Men's Christian associations (Box 93)
      - General
        - 1921-1922 (Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 116
        - 1923-1924 (Folder 2)
      - Student feeding credits
        - General (Folder 3)
        - 1920-1923 (Folder 4)
  - Remittances (Folder 5)
  - Reports
    - General
      - General (Folder 6)
        Available on microfilm reel 117
      - "Report [to the President of the United States] on the Distribution in Russia of the Commodities Received from the Purchasing Commission for Russian Relief, 1922 December 15 (Box 94, Folder 1)
      - "Supplementary Report [to the President of the United States] on the Distribution in Russia of the Commodities Received from the Purchasing Commission for Russian Relief, 1923 September 29 (Folder 2)
    - Baker, G. B. (Folder 3)
    - Bell, W. L. (Folder 4)
    - Bowden, C. G. (Folder 5)
    - Brookhart, Senator. Report on his visit to Russia by John R. Ellingston (Folder 6)
    - Brooks, S. (Folder 7)
      Available on microfilm reel 118
    - Brown, David A. (Folder 8)
    - Brown, Walter Lyman (Folder 9)
    - Cannibalism (Folder 10)
    - Coolidge, A. C. (Folder 11)
    - Dickinson, T. H. (Folder 12)
    - Ellingston, John R. (Folder 13)
    - Fisher, H. H. (Folder 14)
    - Fleming, H. M. (Box 95, Folder 1)
      Available on microfilm reel 119
    - Golder, F. A. See also Hutchinson, Lincoln (Folder 2)
    - Goodrich, J. P. (Folder 3)
    - Haskell, William N. (Folder 4)
    - Hoover, Herbert (Folder 5)
    - Hutchinson, Lincoln
      - General (Folder 6)
        Available on microfilm reel 120
      - General (Box 96, Folder 1)
      - survey, 1923 (Folder 2)
    - Kamenev, Lev (Folder 3)
    - Keeny, S. M. (Folder 4)
    - Kellogg, Vernon Lyman (Folder 5)
    - League of Nations (Folder 6)
      Available on microfilm reel 121
    - Literary Digest (Folder 7)
    - Litvinov, Maksim (Folder 8)
    - Morris, Ira N. (Folder 9)
    - Nansen, Fritjof (Folder 10)
    - National Information Bureau (Box 97, Folder 1)
    - Near East Relief (Folder 2)
    - Rickard, Edgar (Folder 3)
    - Robertson, Benjamin, Sir (Folder 4)
    - Ruhl, Arthur (Folder 5)
    - Shafroth, William C. (Folder 6)
    - U.S. Grain Corporation
      - "Interim Report [to the President of the United States] of the Purchasing Commission for Russian Relief, U.S. Grain Corporation Fiscal Agent,", 1922 March 25 (Folder 7)
        Available on microfilm reel 122
      - "Second Interim Report [to the President of the United States] of the Purchasing Commission for Russian Relief, U.S. Grain Corporation Fiscal Agent,", 1922 June 30 (Folder 8)
      - "Report [to the President of the United States] of the U.S. Grain Corporation Fiscal Agent of the Purchasing Commission for Russian Relief,", 1922 December 15 (Folder 9)
  - Ribinsk (Box 98, Folder 1)
    Available on microfilm reel 123
  - Rostov-Tsaritsyn
    - General (Folder 2)
    - Adult feeding (Folder 3)
    - Allocation recommended (Folder 4)
    - Child feeding (Folder 5)
    - Clothing (Folder 6)
    - Correspondence
      - Miscellaneous (Folder 7)
      - Russian government (Folder 8)
        Available on microfilm reel 124
      - Zone Office (Box 99, Folder 1)
    - Daghestan (Folder 2)
    - Finance (Folder 3)
    - Food remittances (Folder 4)
    - History
      - General (Folder 5)
        Available on microfilm reel 125
      - Bowden, C. G. (Folder 6)
      - Driscoll, J. A. (Folder 7)
      - Verdon, P. S. (Folder 8)
    - Instructions (Folder 9)
    - Kalmucks (Folder 10)
    - Kuban (Folder 11)
    - Reports (Box 100)
      - General (Folder 1)
        Available on microfilm reel 126
      - Inspectors and interpreters (Folder 2)
      - Medical (Folder 3)
        Available on microfilm reel 127
    - Stavropol (Box 101, Folder 1)
    - Telegrams (Folder 2)
    - Transportation (Folder 3)
    - Zonal Representatives Conference (Folder 4)
  - Russian-German Commercial Treaty (Folder 5)
  - Russian press
    - On A.R.A.
      - 1922 (Folder 6)
        Available on microfilm reel 128
      - 1923 (Folder 7)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 102, Folder 1)
        Available on microfilm reel 129
    - On America (Folder 2)
  - Russian Trade Delegation (Folder 3)
  - "Russian Unit Record"
    - 1921 November 20-1922 November 26 (Folder 4)
    - 1922 December 3-1923 June 5 (Box 103, Folder 1-2)
      Available on microfilm reel 130
  - Rye (Folder 3)
  - Salt (Folder 4)
  - Samara (Box 104)
    - General
      - General (Folder 1)
        Available on microfilm reel 131
      - Tables (in Russian) (Folder 2)
    - Adult feeding - Corn (Folder 3)
      Available on microfilm reel 132
    - Allocation recommended (Folder 4)
    - Bath house (Folder 5)
    - Buguruslan (Folder 6)
    - Child feeding (Folder 7)
    - Correspondence with government representative, Mr. Karkluie
      - To (Folder 8)
      - From (Box 105, Folder 1-2)
        Available on microfilm reels 133 and 134
    - Crops (Folder 3)
      Available on microfilm reel 134
    - Finance (Folder 4)
    - History (Ronald H. Allen and Harold M. Fleming) (Box 106, Folder 1)
    - Livestock (Folder 2)
    - Melekes (Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 4)
    - Quakers (Folder 5)
    - Reports
      - General (Folder 6)
        Available on microfilm reel 134A
      - Inspectors (Folder 7)
      - Medical (Box 107, Folder 1)
        Available on microfilm reel 135
    - Statistics (Folder 2)
    - Transportation (Folder 3)
    - Warehouses (Folder 4)
  - Saratov
    - General (Folder 5)
    - Adult feeding (Folder 6)
    - Astrakhan (Folder 7)
      Available on microfilm reel 136
    - Atkarsk (Folder 8)
    - Balakovo (Folder 9)
    - Balashov (Folder 10)
    - Child feeding (Folder 11)
    - Clapp diary (Folder 12)
    - Conference of inspectors, 1922 January-February (Folder 13)
    - Correspondence with government (Box 108, Folder 1-2)
      Available on microfilm reels 136 and 137
    - Dergatcher region (Box 109, Folder 1)
      Available on microfilm reel 138
    - Fedorovka (Folder 2)
    - Finance (Folder 3)
    - Food remittances (Folder 4)
    - German communes (Folder 5)
    - History (John P. Gregg) (Folder 6-10)
    - Kirghiz Republic (Box 110, Folder 1)
      Available on microfilm reel 139
    - Krasni Kut (Folder 2)
    - Liquidation (Folder 3)
    - Medical supplies (Folder 4)
    - Novouzensk (Folder 5)
    - Pokrovsk (Folder 6)
    - Pugachev (Folder 7)
    - Refugees - Soup kitchens (Folder 8)
    - Reports
      - General
        - 1921-1922 (Folder 9)
        - 1923 (Box 111)
          - January-March (Folder 1)
            Available on microfilm reel 140
          - April-May (Folder 2)
      - Gregg, John P. (Folder 3)
      - Medical (Folder 4)
    - Rovnoye (Folder 5)
    - Rtishchevo (Folder 6)
    - Subdistrict correspondence (Box 112)
      - General (Folder 1-2)
        Available on microfilm reel 141
      - With government representatives
        - Balakovskii uezd (Folder 3)
          Available on microfilm reel 141A
        - Fedorovskii region (Box 113, Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 142
        - Miscellaneous (Folder 2)
        - Novouzenskii region (Folder 3)
        - Oblast Nemtsev Povolzhe (Folder 4)
        - Pugachevskii region (Folder 5-6)
          Available on microfilm reels 142 and 143
        - Uralskii region (Folder 7)
          Available on microfilm reel 143
    - Transportation (Folder 8)
    - Uralsk District (Box 114)
      - General
        - General (Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 144
        - In Russian (Folder 2)
      - Weekly reports of Paul S. Clapp, 1921 December 21-1922 June 30 (Folder 3)
  - Scientific aid, 1921-1924 (Box 115, Folder 1)
    Available on microfilm reel 145
  - Shipping
    - General (Folder 2)
      Available on microfilm reel 146
    - Arrivals (Folder 3)
    - Daily position of ships (Folder 4)
    - Ships afloat (Box 116, Folder 1)
      Available on microfilm reel 147
  - Siberia (Folder 2)
  - Simbirsk
    - General (Folder 3)
    - Adult feeding
      - Corn (Folder 4)
      - Soup kitchens (Folder 5)
        Available on microfilm reel 148
    - Alatyr (Folder 6)
    - Allocations (Folder 7)
    - Ardatov (Folder 8)
    - Bugulma (Folder 9)
    - Child feeding (Folder 10)